Welcome to ecFlow!
...
module load: does setup PATH and PYTHONPATH
/usr/local/apps/ecflow/current/bin is usual location
ecFlow is a server, a client, and a GUI: ecflow_ui
ecflow_start.sh is used to start the server, listening ECF_PORT, working in ECF_HOME
ecflow_client is the command line client to load a suite, update it, query the server content...
The definition file describes a suite and its content: tasks and their relations, their triggers, their scripts location.
In this example, the definition file also creates head.h and tail.h file in ECF_INCLUDE directory. They call ecflow_client --init --abort --complete, for the status to change.
Here, the definition file is a python script: by running it, the suite node is placed into ecFlow.
Let's start ecflow_ui: we connect to the local server on ECF_PORT 2500, in this example.
The suite "course" is visible.
We begin it, to get it ready to run.
This suite was designed with default status suspended so that jobs do not start immediately.
Let's open the Info panel, to display Script, Edit tabs.
We can click Preprocess.
We recognise the task wrapper and the headers.
The model task appears in different locations: variables make the difference, for "forecast length", "pertubed forecast number", "control forecast"
We can execute the task, to force the job to start.
Job file is created by ecflow and the Output file is visible.
When we update the GUI, acquisition task is already complete (yellow).
We can open the Table view and configure it to display tasks in submit, active, abort state.
We requeue the completed task, and resume the suite to get it start.
Here the suite completes.
Repeat attribute would get it continue with next forecast date.
let's learn it, practicing the tutorial...